So a few years ago,
几年前，
I did something really brave,
我做了一些非常勇敢的事，
or some would say really stupid.
或许有些人会说很愚蠢的事。
I ran for Congress.
我参选国会议员。
For years, I had existed safely behind the scenes in politics
很多年来，我安全地存在于 政治活动背后
as a fundraiser, as an organizer,
作为资金筹集人，作为组织者，
but in my heart, I always wanted to run.
但我的内心， 我一直希望参选。
The sitting congresswoman had been in my district since 1992.
我所在选区的国会议员女士 从1992年起担任这个职务。
She had never lost a race,
她从未输过一场选战，
and no one had really even run against her in a Democratic primary.
没有人真正认真地 在民主选举中与她竞争。
But in my mind, this was my way
但在我心中，这就是我
to make a difference,
创造不同的方式，
to disrupt the status quo.
改变现状。
The polls, however, told a very different story.
民意调查，然而， 显示出完全不同的故事。
My pollsters told me that I was crazy to run,
我的民调专家告诉我 我要参选简直疯了，
that there was no way that I could win.
我不可能会赢。
But I ran anyway,
但我还是参选了，
and in 2012, I became an upstart in a New York City congressional race.
在2012年，我成了崛起的新秀 参选纽约市国会竞选。
I swore I was going to win.
我发誓我会赢。
I had the endorsement from the New York Daily News,
我得到了《纽约每日新闻》的认可，
the Wall Street Journal snapped pictures of me on election day,
《华尔街日报》刊登了我在选举日的照片，
and CNBC called it one of the hottest races in the country.
美国全国广播公司财经频道称之为 全国范围内最热的选战。
I raised money from everyone I knew,
我从我认识的每个人那里筹钱，
including Indian aunties
包括印度阿姨们
that were just so happy an Indian girl was running.
她们很高兴一个印度女生参选。
But on election day, the polls were right,
但选举日，民调是对的，
and I only got 19 percent of the vote,
我只拿到了19%的选票，
and the same papers that said I was a rising political star
那张曾称我为新兴政治明星的报纸
now said I wasted 1.3 million dollars
现在却说我浪费了130万美金
on 6,321 votes.
在6321张选票上。
Don't do the math.
不要算数字。
It was humiliating.
太丢脸了。
Now, before you get the wrong idea,
现在，在你们得到错误观点前，
this is not a talk about the importance of failure.
这不是一个讲述 失败有多重要的演说。
Nor is it about leaning in.
也不是说女孩要向前一步。
I tell you the story of how I ran for Congress
我讲述的故事是 我如何参选国会议员的
because I was 33 years old
因为我只有33岁
and it was the first time in my entire life
这是我人生中第一次
that I had done something that was truly brave,
做出真正勇敢的事，
where I didn't worry about being perfect.
没有担心完美。
And I'm not alone:
我不是一个人：
so many women I talk to tell me
太多女士曾告诉我
that they gravitate towards careers and professions
她们多么被职业和专业吸引
that they know they're going to be great in,
她们知道她们会做得很好，
that they know they're going to be perfect in,
她们知道她们会非常完美，
and it's no wonder why.
不足为奇。
Most girls are taught to avoid risk and failure.
绝大多数的女孩被教育 来规避风险和失败。
We're taught to smile pretty,
我们被教育要有漂亮的微笑，
play it safe, get all A's.
不要冒险，课程拿全A。
Boys, on the other hand,
男孩们，另一方面来说，
are taught to play rough, swing high,
被教育成要更加勇猛， 冲击更高的目标，
crawl to the top of the monkey bars and then just jump off headfirst.
爬上单杠最高的那层然后往下跳。
And by the time they're adults,
当他们成长为大人，
whether they're negotiating a raise or even asking someone out on a date,
无论他们是在谈判加薪 或是约某人出去玩，
they're habituated to take risk after risk.
他们习惯于接受一个一个挑战。
They're rewarded for it.
他们也为此得到回报奖赏。
It's often said in Silicon Valley,
在矽谷有这样的说法，
no one even takes you seriously unless you've had two failed start-ups.
没人把你当回事 除非你创业失败两次以上。
In other words,
另一句话说，
we're raising our girls to be perfect,
我们教育培养女孩子们追求完美，
and we're raising our boys to be brave.
我们教育培养男孩子们要勇敢。
Some people worry about our federal deficit,
有些人担心我们的联邦赤字，
but I, I worry about our bravery deficit.
但是，我担心我们的勇气赤字。
Our economy, our society, we're just losing out
我们的经济，我们的社会， 我们在遭受损失，
because we're not raising our girls to be brave.
因为我们没有教育女孩子们要勇敢。
The bravery deficit is why women are underrepresented in STEM,
勇气赤字就是为什么女性 在科学技术工程数学（STEM）领域，
in C-suites, in boardrooms, in Congress,
在企业高管层，在董事会，在国会，
and pretty much everywhere you look.
在你所看到的任何地方 都未被充分代表。
In the 1980s, psychologist Carol Dweck
在1980年代，心理学家Carol Dweck
looked at how bright fifth graders handled an assignment
观察研究了五年级学生 如何处理一项
that was too difficult for them.
对他们来说太困难的作业。
She found that bright girls were quick to give up.
她发现，聪明的女孩们很快就放弃了。
The higher the IQ, the more likely they were to give up.
智商越高的女孩， 放弃的可能性越大。
Bright boys, on the other hand,
男孩们，
found the difficult material to be a challenge.
将困难的材料视为一个挑战。
They found it energizing.
他们为此精力充沛。
They were more likely to redouble their efforts.
他们更倾向于双倍努力。
What's going on?
发生了什么？
Well, at the fifth grade level,
嗯，在五年级，
girls routinely outperform boys in every subject,
女孩总的来说比男孩 在各个科目的表现都要好，
including math and science,
包括数学和科学，
so it's not a question of ability.
所以这不是能力的问题。
The difference is in how boys and girls approach a challenge.
不同点在于男孩和女孩 如何看待挑战。
And it doesn't just end in fifth grade.
这不止于五年级。
An HP report found that men will apply for a job
一份惠普报告指出 男性会递出工作申请
if they meet only 60 percent of the qualifications,
如果他们只达到60%的招聘要求，
but women, women will apply
而女性，女性只有在
only if they meet 100 percent of the qualifications.
100%达到招聘要求的时候 才会递出申请。
100 percent.
百分之百。
This study is usually invoked as evidence that, well,
这份研究通常会被作为 证据来说，嗯，
women need a little more confidence.
女性需要更多的自信。
But I think it's evidence
但我认为这是证据
that women have been socialized to aspire to perfection,
说明女性长期被赋予 追逐完美，
and they're overly cautious.
她们太过谨慎了。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
And even when we're ambitious,
即使是当我们雄心勃勃，
even when we're leaning in,
即使我们向前一步，
that socialization of perfection
社会对完美的要求
has caused us to take less risks in our careers.
让我们在职业发展中 选择冒更小的风险。
And so those 600,000 jobs that are open right now
现在，在计算机和科技领域，
in computing and tech,
有六十万个开放申请的工作职位，
women are being left behind,
女性被抛在了后面，
and it means our economy is being left behind
这也意味着我们的经济 被远远抛在了后面
on all the innovation and problems women would solve
女性可以解决的创新和难题
if they were socialized to be brave
如果女性被教育要勇敢
instead of socialized to be perfect.
而不是完美。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
So in 2012, I started a company to teach girls to code,
在2012年，我创办了一家公司 教女孩如何编程，
and what I found is that by teaching them to code
我发现，通过教她们如何编程
I had socialized them to be brave.
我令她们更加勇敢。
Coding, it's an endless process of trial and error,
编程，是一个无止尽的过程 实验和错误，
of trying to get the right command in the right place,
试着将对的指令放在合适的地方，
with sometimes just a semicolon
有时只是一个分号
making the difference between success and failure.
就能决定成功还是失败。
Code breaks and then it falls apart,
编码出错了随后七零八落，
and it often takes many, many tries
时常需要很多很多次试验
until that magical moment
直到那个神奇的时刻
when what you're trying to build comes to life.
你想要搭建的程序完成了。
It requires perseverance.
它需要持之以恒的努力。
It requires imperfection.
需要接受不完美。
We immediately see in our program
我们立即发现在项目里
our girls' fear of not getting it right,
女孩们害怕出错，
of not being perfect.
害怕不完美。
Every Girls Who Code teacher tells me the same story.
每个女孩的指导老师 都和我说一样的故事。
During the first week, when the girls are learning how to code,
在第一周， 当女孩们试着学习如何编程，
a student will call her over and she'll say,
一个学生叫她过去 她说到，
"I don't know what code to write."
“我不知道要写那个编码。”
The teacher will look at her screen,
当老师看她的屏幕，
and she'll see a blank text editor.
会看到一个完全空白的界面。
If she didn't know any better, she'd think that her student
如果她不知道原因的话， 她也许会想
spent the past 20 minutes just staring at the screen.
她的学生在过去的20分钟里 只是盯着屏幕发呆。
But if she presses undo a few times,
但如果她点击几下撤销键，
she'll see that her student wrote code and then deleted it.
他就会看到她的学生 写了代码随后又删掉了它们。
She tried, she came close,
她尝试了，她接近目标了，
but she didn't get it exactly right.
但是她没有完全答对。
Instead of showing the progress that she made,
比起展现她经历的过程，
she'd rather show nothing at all.
她宁可什么都不展现。
Perfection or bust.
要么完美要么什么也没有。
It turns out that our girls are really good at coding,
结果显示女孩们 非常善于编程，
but it's not enough just to teach them to code.
但教给她们如何写代码 是完全不够的。
My friend Lev Brie, who is a professor at the University of Columbia
我的朋友Lev Brie， 是哥伦比亚大学的教授
and teaches intro to Java
他教授Java编程
tells me about his office hours with computer science students.
他告诉我他对电脑科学学生开放的 咨询时间里发生的故事。
When the guys are struggling with an assignment,
当男生们艰难应对一个作业的时候，
they'll come in and they'll say,
他们会过来然后说，
"Professor, there's something wrong with my code."
“教授，我编的程序 出了点问题。”
The girls will come in and say,
女生们会过来然后说，
"Professor, there's something wrong with me."
“教授，我出了点问题。”
We have to begin to undo the socialization of perfection,
我们必须要撤销 对女性社会化的完美主义，
but we've got to combine it with building a sisterhood
我们必须要将这和 建立女性支持系统一起
that lets girls know that they are not alone.
让女孩们知道 她们并不孤单。
Because trying harder is not going to fix a broken system.
因为再努力地尝试 也无法修补一个破裂的系统。
I can't tell you how many women tell me,
太多的女性朋友告诉我，
"I'm afraid to raise my hand,
“我害怕举手发言，
I'm afraid to ask a question,
我害怕问问题，
because I don't want to be the only one
因为我不想做那个
who doesn't understand,
那个唯一不懂的人，
the only one who is struggling.
那个唯一挣扎的人。
When we teach girls to be brave
当我们教女孩们要勇敢
and we have a supportive network cheering them on,
我们要有支持她们的系统 来鼓励她们，
they will build incredible things,
她们会有伟大的成就，
and I see this every day.
我每天都看到这些事。
Take, for instance, two of our high school students
举个例子， 两个高中学生
who built a game called Tampon Run --
制作了一个游戏叫做 卫生棉逃亡-- （译者注：和游戏”神庙逃亡“谐音）
yes, Tampon Run --
对，卫生棉逃亡--
to fight against the menstruation taboo
来反对游戏中的月经标记
and sexism in gaming.
和对女性的歧视。
Or the Syrian refugee
或是叙利亚难民
who dared show her love for her new country
她展示了对新国家的爱
by building an app to help Americans get to the polls.
制作了一款应用程序 让美国人轻松了解民调。
Or a 16-year-old girl who built an algorithm
或是一个16岁的女孩 她建立了一套运算系统
to help detect whether a cancer is benign or malignant
来帮助测算癌症是 良性的还是恶性的，
in the off chance that she can save her daddy's life
抱着一丝希望能救她
because he has cancer.
患癌症的父亲。
These are just three examples of thousands,
这只是成千上万个例子中的三个，
thousands of girls who have been socialized to be imperfect,
成千上万个女孩 被社会化为不完美的，
who have learned to keep trying, who have learned perseverance.
她们学习如何不断尝试， 学着如何持之以恒。
And whether they become coders
无论她们未来会成为程序员
or the next Hillary Clinton or Beyoncé,
或是下一个希拉里·克林顿 或是碧昂斯，
they will not defer their dreams.
她们不会推迟自己的梦想。
And those dreams have never been more important for our country.
这些梦想对我们国家来说 是多么重要。
For the American economy, for any economy to grow,
对美国的经济， 对任何成长中的经济，
to truly innovate,
对真正的创新开发，
we cannot leave behind half our population.
我们不能丢下半数的人口。
We have to socialize our girls to be comfortable with imperfection,
我们需要社会化地教女孩们 适应习惯不完美，
and we've got to do it now.
我们现在开始就要这样做。
We cannot wait for them to learn how to be brave like I did
我们不能等到她们 自己去学习如何勇敢
when I was 33 years old.
就像我33岁时那样。
We have to teach them to be brave in schools
我们要教她们勇敢 在学校
and early in their careers,
在职业起步的时期，
when it has the most potential to impact their lives
在能够影响她们的人生 以及其他人的人生
and the lives of others,
重要的时期，
and we have to show them that they will be loved and accepted
要让她们知道 她们会被爱被接受
not for being perfect
不是因为完美
but for being courageous.
而是因为充满勇气。
And so I need each of you to tell every young woman you know --
我需要你们每个人 告诉你认识的每个年轻女士 --
your sister, your niece, your employee, your colleague --
你的姐妹，你的侄女， 你的雇员，你的同事 --
to be comfortable with imperfection,
习惯接受不完美，
because when we teach girls to be imperfect,
因为当我们告诉女孩 不必完美的时候，
and we help them leverage it,
我们帮助她们平衡这样的关系，
we will build a movement of young women who are brave
我们会有更多勇敢的年轻女士
and who will build a better world for themselves
这些女士为她们自己
and for each and every one of us.
和我们每个人建立更好的世界。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
Thank you.
谢谢。
Chris Anderson: Reshma, thank you.
克里斯·安德森：Reshma，谢谢你。
It's such a powerful vision you have. You have a vision.
这是非常强大的憧憬。 你很有眼光。
Tell me how it's going.
现在进行的怎么样了。
How many girls are involved now in your program?
现在有多少女孩 加入了你的项目活动？
Reshma Saujani: Yeah. So in 2012, we taught 20 girls.
Reshma Saujani：是的。 在2012年，有20个女孩参与。
This year we'll teach 40,000 in all 50 states.
今年，我们有4万名女孩 来自美国50个州。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
And that number is really powerful,
这个数字真的很厉害，
because last year we only graduated 7,500 women in computer science.
因为去年我们只有7500名女性 拿到电脑科学的学位。
Like, the problem is so bad
问题很严重
that we can make that type of change quickly.
所以我们才能快速做出改变。
CA: And you're working with some of the companies in this room even,
CA：你和现在会场里一些公司合作
who are welcoming graduates from your program?
它们欢迎你结业于 你的项目的学生吗？
RS: Yeah, we have about 80 partners,
RS：是的，我们有 大概80个合作公司，
from Twitter to Facebook
从推特到脸书
to Adobe to IBM to Microsoft to Pixar to Disney,
还有Adobe，IBM，微软 皮克斯，还有迪斯尼，
I mean, every single company out there.
我是说，每一家公司。
And if you're not signed up, I'm going to find you,
如果你还没和我们签合作， 我会去找你，
because we need every single tech company
因为我们需要每个科技公司
to embed a Girls Who Code classroom in their office.
都有能够编程的女孩 在他们的办公室工作。
CA: And you have some stories back from some of those companies
CA：你有一些故事 来自于那些公司
that when you mix in more gender balance
当公司性别更平等的时候
in the engineering teams, good things happen.
在工程队，有好事情发生。
RS: Great things happen.
RS：太棒的事情了。
I mean, I think that it's crazy to me to think about the fact
我是说，对我来说这样的事实 简直令人发疯
that right now 85 percent of all consumer purchases are made by women.
85%的消费行为来自于女性。
Women use social media at a rate of 600 percent more than men.
女性使用社交媒体的比率 是男性的六倍。
We own the Internet,
我们拥有网络，
and we should be building the companies of tomorrow.
我们未来会创建公司。
And I think when companies have diverse teams,
我想，当公司的团队 更加多元化，
and they have incredible women that are part of their engineering teams,
他们的工程队有卓越的女性，
they build awesome things, and we see it every day.
他们会建造美好的建筑， 我们每天都看到这些。
CA: Reshma, you saw the reaction there. You're doing incredibly important work.
CA：Reshma，你看到了现场观众的反应。 你在做卓越又重要的工作。
This whole community is cheering you on. More power to you. Thank you.
整个群体都在为你欢呼打气。 希望你更加成功。谢谢。
RS: Thank you.
RS：谢谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）